simplehelp.net 2019-04-21

# Privacy Policy

## Who we are

We are a small (one person) company. Our revenue is generated from solely from ads displayed by [Google’s AdSense](https://www.google.com/adsense/) (you can find all of their privacy policies [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy)) and [Ziff Davis](https://www.ziffdavis.com/) (you can find their privacy policy [here](https://www.ziffdavis.com/privacy-policy)) as well as referral fees from users who sign up for [Private Internet Access](https://www.privateinternetaccess.com/pages/buy-vpn/simplehelp) via referral links on this site. We do not sell _anything_. 

Our website address is: [https://www.simplehelp.net](https://www.simplehelp.net/)

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available [here](https://automattic.com/privacy/). After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year. Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

We use [Google’s Analytics service](https://www.google.com/analytics/) to keep track of things like ‘most visited page’ and ‘most common Operating System’ so that we know which topics to write about. 

### Who we share your data with

Absolutely no one. 

### How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have left one or more comments on this site, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service, Akismet. From Akismet: “We collect information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect depends on how the User sets up Akismet for the Site, but typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).” Please remember, this information is only collected and sent to Akismet if you leave a comment. 

### Contact information

Can be found on the “[contact us](https://www.simplehelp.net/feedback/)” page.
